漫威影业
新墨西哥州  旧桥市
等着吧
Wait for it.
-我能开收音机吗  -不能
- Can I turn on the radio? - No.
简  你不能一直这样下去了
Jane, you can't keep doing this.
最近17次事件都能精确预测到秒
The last 17 occurrences have been predictable to the second.
简  你是天文物理学家
Jane, you're an astrophysicist,
不是什么追风者
not some storm chaser.
我跟你说了  大气波动
I'm telling you, there's a connection
和我的研究有很大关系
between these atmospheric disturbances and my research.
艾瑞克  如果没有十足把握
Erik, I wouldn't have asked you
我是不会让你大老远飞过来的
to fly out here if I wasn't absolutely sure.
简
Jane?
你最好看看这个
I think you want to see this.
那是什么
What is that?
你不是说会是微弱的极光吗
I thought you said it was a subtle aurora!
快开车
Go!
-靠近点  -好啊  很好
- Get closer. - Right. Good one.
快点
Go!
红外线正片模式
你干什么
What are you doing?
我才不要为六个学分去送死呢
I am not dying for six college credits!
别别别
No, no, no.
法律上讲  是你的错
I think that was legally your fault.
去拿急救箱
Get the first aid kit.
帮帮忙  千万别死
Do me a favor and don't be dead.
求你了
Please.
他是从哪来的
Where did he come from?
挪威  滕斯贝格  公元965年
曾经
Once,
人类接受了一个简单的真相
mankind accepted a simple truth,
在这个宇宙里  他们并不孤独
that they were not alone in this universe.
有些地方是他们心中神的家园
Some worlds man believed to be home to their gods.
另一些地方  他们则心存畏惧
Others, they knew to fear.
在一个寒冷黑暗的国度  有一群冰霜巨人
From a realm of cold and darkness came the Frost Giants,
他们威胁要将人类世界带入新的冰河世纪
threatening to plunge the mortal world into a new ice age.
不过人类不必独自面对这个威胁
But humanity would not face this threat alone.
我们的军队将冰霜巨人
Our armies drove the Frost Giants
打回了自己的老窝
back into the heart of their own world.
损失非常惨重
The cost was great.
最后
In the end,
他们的国王倒下了
their king fell.
他们的能量之源也被带走了
And the source of their power was taken from them.
随着最后一场大战的终结
With the last great war ended,
我们离开其它世界  回到了家园
we withdrew from the other worlds and returned home
永恒之国
to the Realm Eternal,
阿斯加德
Asgard.
在这里  我们是希望的灯塔
Here we remain as a beacon of hope,
在星际间普撒光辉
shining out across the stars.
虽然我们成为了人类的神话和传说
And though we have fallen into man's myths and legends,
但其实是阿斯加德
it was Asgard
和它的战士们
and its warriors
为宇宙
that brought peace
带来了和平
to the universe.
不过  那一天终会来的
But the day will come
到时候  你们中的一个
when one of you
必须保卫这和平
will have to defend that peace.
冰霜巨人依然活着吗
Do the Frost Giants still live?
等我当了王
When I'm king,
我会追捕怪兽  把它们都杀光
I'll hunt the monsters down and slay them all!
就像您做的一样  父王
Just as you did, Father.
一位明君
A wise king
从不挑起战争  但是...
never seeks out war. But
他必须时刻准备好应对战争
he must always be ready for it.
-我准备好了  父王  -我也是
- I'm ready, Father. - So am I.
你们中只有一个能登上王位
Only one of you can ascend to the throne.
但你们两个  都是生而为王的
But both of you were born to be kings.
拜托
Oh, please.
托尔·奥丁森
Thor Odinson,
同北欧起名旧习
父亲名字+son作为儿子姓氏
我的继承人
my heir,
我的长子
my firstborn.
强大的雷神之锤被托付给你已久
So long entrusted with the mighty hammer Mjolnir,
此锤由濒死恒星的内核锻造而成
forged in the heart of a dying star,
威力无可匹敌
its power has no equal,
它是用以毁灭的武器
as a weapon to destroy
亦可成为建造的工具
or as a tool to build.
与国王的身份相匹配
'Tis a fit companion for a king.
我从时间开始之初
I have defended Asgard
就保卫着阿斯加德
and the lives of the innocent across the Nine Realms
以及九大王国的无辜生灵
from the time of the great beginning.
不过这一天已经来到了
Though the day has come...
你是否发誓保卫九大王国
Do you swear to guard the Nine Realms?
我发誓
I swear.
你是否发誓维护和平
And do you swear to preserve the peace?
我发誓
I swear.
你是否发誓
Do you swear
摒弃一切私图野心
to cast aside all selfish ambition
只为王国做有益之事
and to pledge yourself only to the good of the Realms?
我发誓
I swear!
那么  今天
Then, on this day,
我  众神之父奥丁
I, Odin Allfather,
宣布你
proclaim you...
冰霜巨人
The Frost Giants!
约顿巨人必须为他们的所作所为付出代价
The Jotuns must pay for what they've done!
他们已经付出了生命代价
They have paid, with their lives.
毁灭者履行了自己的职责
The Destroyer did its work,
远古冬棺是安全的  一切都好
the Casket is safe, and all is well.
一切都好
All is well?
他们攻进了武器库
They broke into the weapons vault!
倘若冰霜巨人偷走了任何一件圣物
If the Frost Giants had stolen even one of these relics...
-他们并没有  -我想知道为什么
- They didn't. - Well, I want to know why!
我和约顿之王劳菲有休战协定
I have a truce with Laufey, King of the Jotuns.
他刚刚打破了休战
He just broke your truce!
他们知道你是有弱点的
They know you are vulnerable!
你准备采取什么行动
What action would you take?
像您曾经一样  进军约顿海姆
March into Jotunheim as you once did.
给他们一个教训
Teach them a lesson.
让他们吓破胆
Break their spirits
这样他们就再不敢来进犯了
so they'll never dare try to cross our borders again.
你只是站在一个战士的角度思考
You're thinking only as a warrior.
这就是战争行为
This was an act of war!
这只是一小部分人  注定失败的行为
It was the act of but a few, doomed to fail.
看看他们都到哪了
Look how far they got!
我们会找到防御漏洞并修补好的
We will find the breach in our defenses and it will be sealed.
作为阿斯加德的王
As King of Asgard...
但你不是王
But you're not king!
现在还不是
Not yet.
现在来陪我可不明智  弟弟
It's unwise to be in my company right now, brother.
这本该是我的荣耀之日
This was to be my day of triumph.
那一天会来的
It'll come.
迟早会来的
In time.
这是怎么了
What's this?
如果这么说能安慰你的话
If it's any consolation,
我觉得你是对的
I think you're right.
关于冰霜巨人  关于劳菲  关于一切
About the Frost Giants, about Laufey, about everything.
如果他们能突破阿斯加德的防御一次
If they found a way to penetrate Asgard's defenses once,
谁能保证他们不会卷土重来呢
who's to say they won't try again?
-下一次会带着军队来  -正是
- Next time with an army. - Exactly.
但你的任何行动  都会违背父王的意愿
There's nothing you can do without defying Father.
不不不  我了解这表情
No, no, no. I know that look.
这是确保我们防御安全的唯一方法
That's the only way to ensure the safety of our borders.
托尔  这是发疯
Thor, it's madness.
发疯  哪种程度的发疯
Madness? What sort of madness?
我们要去约顿海姆
We're going to Jotunheim.
什么
What?
这可不像去趟地球
This isn't like a journey to Earth
在那里你只要稍稍召唤些闪电雷鸣
where you summon a little lightning and thunder,
人类就会把你当成神来崇拜
and the mortals worship you as a god.
这可是约顿海姆
This is Jotunheim.
我父王曾一路攻入约顿海姆
My father fought his way into Jotunheim,
击败了他们的军队  带走了他们的远古冬棺
defeated their armies and took their Casket.
我们只是去寻求回应
We would just be looking for answers.
这是被禁止的
It is forbidden!
朋友们  你们忘了我们一起做过的事吗
My friends, have you forgotten all that we have done together?
范达尔  霍根
Fandral, Hogun.
是谁带你们加入了最光荣的战役
Who led you into the most glorious of battles?
是你
You did.
沃斯塔格  是谁给了你鲜美的佳肴
And Volstagg, to delicacies so succulent,
让你觉得欲仙欲死  仿佛升入了英灵殿呢
you thought you'd died and gone to Valhalla?
是你
You did.
没错
Yes!
又是谁向所有认为
And who proved wrong all who scoffed at the idea
少女不能成为王国最威猛的战士的人
that a young maiden could be one of the fiercest warriors
证明了他们的错误呢
this realm has ever known?
是我
I did.
的确  但我一直支持你  希芙
True, but I supported you, Sif.
朋友们
My friends,
我们要去约顿海姆
we're going to Jotunheim.
交给我吧
You leave this to me.
-好海姆达尔...  -你们穿得不够暖
- Good Heimdall... - You're not dressed warmly enough.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
你们以为能瞒过我吗
Do you think that you can deceive me?
-你一定是搞错了  -够了
- You must be mistaken... - Enough!
海姆达尔  能让我们过去吗
Heimdall, may we pass?
从没有敌人能逃过我的眼睛  直到今天
Never has an enemy slipped my watch until this day.
我想知道究竟是怎么回事
I wish to know how that happened.
那就在我们回来之前
Then tell no one where we have gone
别告诉任何人我们的去向
until we've returned.
明白了吗
Understand?
怎么了  三寸不烂之舌打结了
What happened? Silver tongue turn to lead?
我警告你们
Be warned.
作为门卫
I will honor my sworn oath
我将遵守保护王国的誓言
to protect this realm as its Gatekeeper.
如果你们的归来威胁了阿斯加德的安全
If your return threatens the safety of Asgard,
彩虹桥将不会为你们开启
Bifrost will remain closed to you
你将被留在约顿海姆的寒冷荒漠中等死
and you'll be left to die in the cold waste of Jotunheim.
你不能干脆为我们一直开着桥吗
Couldn't you just leave the bridge open for us?
一直开启
To leave the bridge open
会释放彩虹桥的全部能量
would unleash the full power of the Bifrost
摧毁连你们在内的整个约顿海姆
and destroy Jotunheim with you upon it.
我可不准备今天死
I have no plans to die today.
没人想死
None do.
我们不该来的
We shouldn't be here.
走吧
Let's move.
他们在哪
Where are they?
躲起来了
Hiding,
懦夫的惯用伎俩
as cowards always do.
你们这么大老远来送死  阿斯加德人
You've come a long way to die, Asgardians.
我是托尔·奥丁森
I am Thor Odinson!
我们知道你是谁
We know who you are.
你们的人是怎么进入阿斯加德的
How did your people get into Asgard?
奥丁之家满是叛徒
The House of Odin is full of traitors.
不要用谎言污蔑我父王之名
Do not dishonor my father's name with your lies!
你父亲是个刽子手  是个小偷
Your father is a murderer and a thief!
你们又为什么而来  来讲和吗
And why have you come here? To make peace?
你期待战争  你渴望它
You long for battle. You crave it.
你不过是个
You're nothing but a boy
想证明自己是大人的小男孩
trying to prove himself a man.
本"男孩"厌倦了你的嘲笑
Well, this "boy" has grown tired of your mockery.
托尔  三思而后行
Thor, stop and think.
看看你周围  我们寡不敌众
Look around you, we're outnumbered.
记住你的位置  弟弟
Know your place, brother.
你不知道自己的行为将导致什么
You know not what your actions would unleash.
可我知道
I do.
走吧  趁我还没改主意
Go now, while I still allow it.
我们将接受您最宽仁的提议
We will accept your most gracious offer.
走吧  哥哥
Come on, brother.
滚回家吧  小公主
Run back home, little princess.
该死
Damn.
谁是下一个
Next?
至少给我点挑战嘛
At least make it a challenge for me!
这才像样
That's more like it.
别让他们碰到你
Don't let them touch you!
托尔
Thor!
-我们必须走了  -那就走吧
- We must go! - Then go!
快跑
Run!
托尔
Thor!
海姆达尔
Heimdall!
开启彩虹桥
Open the bridge!
父王  我们一起消灭他们
Father! We'll finish them together!
闭嘴
Silence!
众神之父
Allfather.
你看上去很疲惫
You look weary.
劳菲
Laufey,
就此打住吧
end this now.
是你儿子挑起的
Your boy sought this out.
没错
You're right.
这不过是男孩的胡闹  别小题大作
And these are the actions of a boy, treat them as such.
你我可以就此做个了结
You and I can end this here and now,
不要引发进一步的杀戮
before there's further bloodshed.
事情已经超出外交范围了  众神之父
We are beyond diplomacy now, Allfather.
他会得到他想要的
He'll get what he came for.
战争
War
还有死亡
and death.
那好吧
So be it.
为什么把我们带回来
Why did you bring us back?
你知道自己做了什么  挑起了什么吗
Do you realize what you've done? What you've started?
我在保卫我的家园
I was protecting my home.
你连自己的朋友都保护不了
You cannot even protect your friends!
又凭什么保护这个王国
How can you hope to protect a kingdom?
带他去疗伤  立刻
Get him to the healing room! Now!
如果惧怕行动  王国就要灭亡了
There won't be a kingdom to protect
还保卫什么
if you're afraid to act.
约顿巨人必须像曾经惧怕你一样学着惧怕我
The Jotuns must learn to fear me, just as they once feared you.
这是骄傲和自负  不是领导能力
That's pride and vanity talking, not leadership.
你忘了我教过你的一切
You've forgotten everything I taught you
战士的耐心
about a warrior's patience.
就在你等待和忍耐的时候
While you wait and be patient,
九大王国都在嘲笑我们
the Nine Realms laugh at us.
老路走不通了
The old ways are done.
你眼见阿斯加德衰落  却只会夸夸其谈
You'd stand giving speeches while Asgard falls.
你是个虚荣  贪婪  残暴的孩子
You are a vain, greedy, cruel boy!
你是个愚蠢的老头
And you are an old man and a fool!
是啊
Yes.
我是愚蠢的
I was a fool
以为你已经准备好了
to think you were ready.
父王
Father...
托尔·奥丁森
Thor Odinson,
你违抗了国王的明确指令
you have betrayed the express command of your king.
由于你的傲慢和愚蠢
Through your arrogance and stupidity,
和平的王国和无辜的生灵
you've opened these peaceful realms and innocent lives
将面临战争的恐怖和惨景
to the horror and desolation of war!
你愧对这些王国
You are unworthy of these realms!
愧对你的头衔
You're unworthy of your title!
你愧对
You're unworthy
你所背叛的爱你之人
of the loved ones you have betrayed.
现在  我要收回你的能力
I now take from you your power!
以我父亲
In the name of my father
及祖父的名义
and his father before,
我  众神之父奥丁  将你驱逐
I, Odin Allfather, cast you out!
不管是谁持有此锤  只要他配得上
Whosoever holds this hammer, if he be worthy,
就将拥有雷神之力
shall possess the power of Thor.
法律上讲  是你的错
I think that was legally your fault.
去拿急救箱
Get the first aid kit.
帮帮忙  千万别死
Do me a favor and don't be dead.
需要做心肺复苏吗
Does he need CPR?
我可会做心肺复苏了
Because I totally know CPR.
他从哪来的
Where did he come from?
你还好吗
You all right?
锤子
Hammer?
我们看得出你喝高了  挺明显的
Yeah, we can tell you're hammered. It's pretty obvious.
上帝啊  艾瑞克  看看这个
Oh, my God. Erik, look at this!
我们得在一切变化之前赶快行动
We have to move quickly before this all changes.
简  我们得送他去医院
Jane, we have to take him to the hospital.
-父王  -他好着呢  看看他
- Father! - He's fine, look at him.
海姆达尔
Heimdall!
我知道你能听见我  开启彩虹桥
I know you can hear me! Open the Bifrost!
医院  你去  我留下
Hospital. You go, I'll stay.
你  这是哪个王国
You. What realm is this?
艾尔夫海姆  诺恩海姆
Alfheim? Nornheim?
新墨西哥
New Mexico?
你胆敢用这么小的武器威胁我  托尔
You dare threaten me, Thor, with so puny a weapon?
咋了  他吓着我了
What? He was freaking me out!
下次你要电击一个人的话
Next time you decide to taser somebody,
确保他已经在车里了   好吗
make sure he's already in the car, okay?
简  走吧
Jane! Come on.
县医院
姓名
Name?
他说他叫托尔
He said it was Thor?
托  尔
T-h-o-r.
你和他什么关系
And your relationship to him?
根本不认识
I've never met him before.
直到她开车撞倒了他
Until she hit him with a car.
只是擦到了他  但她把他电晕了
I grazed him, but she tasered him.
没错
Yes, I did.
只是抽点血
Just taking a little blood.
你胆敢袭击奥丁之子
How dare you attack the son of Odin?
快来帮忙
I need some help!
叫保安来
Call security!
保安速到三号急诊室  马上
Security to ER 3, stat!
你们打不过伟大的...
You're no match for the Mighty...
旧桥市市界
你说这不是单纯的磁暴吧
You don't think this was just a magnetic storm, do you?
看  边缘处的透镜作用
Look, the lensing around these edges
是爱因斯坦-罗森桥的特征
is characteristic of an Einstein-Rosen Bridge.
什么桥
A what?
-你不是科学专业的吗  -政治科学
- I thought you were a science major? - Political science.
她是唯一的申请人
She was the only applicant.
爱因斯坦-罗森桥是可能存在的
An Einstein-Rosen Bridge is a theoretical connection
两个不同时空的连接带
between two different points of space-time.
就是个虫洞
It's a wormhole.
-艾瑞克  你看到了什么  -星星
- Erik, look. What do you see? - Stars.
对  但不是我们的星星
Yeah, but not our stars.
看  这是我们这象限
See, this is the star alignment
每年这时候的星体排布
for our quadrant this time of year,
除非小熊星座休假了
and unless Ursa Minor decided to take a day off,
否则这就是别处的星座
these are someone else's constellations.
快看这个
Check this out.
不  不可能
No, it can't be.
我想我有东西落在医院了
I think I left something at the hospital.
这不可能
It's not possible!
县医院
不知他是吸毒还是怎么的  突然就发飙
He was on drugs or something. He just went nuts.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我刚把一件最重要的证据弄丢了
I just lost my most important piece of evidence.
又这样
Typical.
-现在怎么办  -找到他
- So now what? - We find him.
你看到他在医院都干了什么吗
Did you see what he did in there?
去找他未必是个好主意
I'm not sure finding him is the best idea.
我们的数据无法说明
Well, our data can't tell us
处于磁暴之中是什么感觉
what it was like to be inside that event,
但他能  所以我们得找到他
and he can. So, we're gonna find him.
好吧
Okay.
看来得找遍整个新墨西哥了  对吧
So we're gonna look all over New Mexico, right?
没错
Exactly.
什么
What?
对不起  我发誓我不是故意老撞你的
I'm so sorry. I swear I'm not doing this on purpose.
我来  我来
I got it, I got it.
加油  搞定它
Come on, kick it in now!
拔起来了吗
Did it work?
长官  我们找到了
Sir, we found it.
作为一个疯子流浪汉  他太正点了
You know, for a crazy homeless person, he's pretty cut.
抱歉我电了你
Hey, sorry I tased you!
别动  别动
Excuse me, excuse me!
这是什么
What is this?
你好  我的名字叫唐纳德·布莱克医生
我前男友的
My ex.
很会和病人相处  却不会跟我相处
Good with patients and bad with relationships.
只有这衣服合你身了
They're the only clothes I had that would fit you.
足矣
They will suffice.
不用客气
You're welcome.
这具人类躯体变弱了
This mortal form has grown weak.
我需要进食
I need sustenance.
我们不该让他去的
We should never have let him go.
没人能阻止他
There was no stopping him.
他只是被放逐了  又不是死了
Well, at least he's only banished, not dead.
要不是守护
Which is what we'd all be
把我们的去向告诉了奥丁  我们可就没命了
if that guard hadn't told Odin where we'd gone.
守护是怎么知道的
How did the guard even know?
我告诉他的
I told him.
什么
What?
我叫他在我们走后把这事告诉奥丁
I told him to go to Odin after we'd left.
他动作太慢了  该挨顿鞭子
He should be flogged for taking so long.
我们本该在到约顿海姆前被拦下
We should never have reached Jotunheim.
是你告诉守护的
You told the guard?
我救了我们的命
I saved our lives.
还有托尔的
And Thor's.
我压根没想到父王会因此放逐他
I had no idea Father would banish him for what he did.
洛基
Loki.
你得去找众神之父
You must go to the Allfather
劝他收回成命
and convince him to change his mind.
我去了又能如何
And if I do, then what?
我比你们都更爱托尔
I love Thor more dearly than any of you,
但你们知道他是怎样的人
but you know what he is.
高傲  鲁莽  极其危险
He's arrogant. He's reckless. He's dangerous.
你们看到他今天的所作所为了
You saw how he was today.
这是阿斯加德的国王该有的样子吗
Is that what Asgard needs from its king?
他嘴上说是为了阿斯加德好
He may speak of the good of Asgard,
但他一直嫉妒托尔
but he's always been jealous of Thor.
我们得感谢他
We should be grateful to him,
是他救了我们的命
he saved our lives.
劳菲曾说
Laufey said
奥丁之家里有叛徒
there were traitors in the House of Odin.
魔法大师有能力将三个约顿巨人带进阿斯加德
A master of magic could bring three Jotuns into Asgard.
洛基一向喜欢恶作剧
Loki's always been one for mischief,
但你说的可是相当严重的事
but you're talking about something else entirely.
放下
Stop!
我被诅咒了吗
Am I cursed?
没有
No.
我到底是什么人
What am I?
你是我儿子
You're my son.
此外呢
What more than that?
远古冬棺并不是
The Casket wasn't the
你那天从约顿海姆夺来的唯一东西吧
only thing you took from Jotunheim that day, was it?
没错
No.
战后
In the aftermath of the battle,
我走进神殿  发现了一个婴儿
I went into the temple and I found a baby.
巨人族的幼小后代
Small for a giant's offspring.
被遗弃  很痛苦  等着自生自灭
Abandoned, suffering, left to die.
是劳菲的儿子
Laufey's son.
劳菲的儿子
没错
Yes.
为什么
Why?
你杀约顿巨人无数  为何要带我走
You were knee-deep in Jotuns blood, why would you take me?
你只是无辜的孩子
You were an innocent child.
不  你带走我另有目的  是什么
No. You took me for a purpose. What was it?
告诉我
Tell me!
我希望有朝一日两族能联合
I thought we could unite our kingdoms one day.
形成同盟  带来永久和平
Bring about an alliance, bring about permanent peace.
通过你
Through you.
什么
What?
但那一切都无关紧要了
But those plans no longer matter.
这么说  我不过是又一件被盗纪念品
So I am no more than another stolen relic,
被困在此  等着某天派上用场
locked up here until you might have use of me.
你为什么要曲解我的意思
Why do you twist my words?
你本可从一开始就告诉我我的身份
You could have told me what I was from the beginning,
你为什么没说
why didn't you?
你是我儿子
You're my son.
我只是想保护你  不被真相伤害
I wanted only to protect you from the truth.
怎么
What?
因为我是孩子们睡前
Because I'm the monster
父母用来吓唬他们的怪兽吗
parents tell their children about at night?
-不是的  -现在一切都说得通了
- No, no. - You know, it all makes sense now!
为什么多年来你一直偏爱托尔
Why you favored Thor all these years!
因为无论你怎么说你爱我
Because no matter how much you claim to love me,
你绝不会让冰霜巨人
you could never have a Frost Giant
坐上阿斯加德的王座
sitting on the throne of Asgard!
卫兵
Guards!
卫兵  快点  帮帮我
Guards, please, help!
你是怎么到那片云里去的
How'd you get inside that cloud?
还有  你怎么能吃了一整盒糕点
Also, how could you eat an entire box of Pop-Tarts
还饿成这样
and still be this hungry?
这饮料  我喜欢
This drink, I like it.
是啊  很不错吧
I know. It's great, right?
再来
Another!
对不起  伊奇  小意外
Sorry, Lzzy. Little accident.
-你什么意思  -很美味  我还想来一杯
- What was that? - It was delicious. I want another.
-你可以直接说啊  -我说了啊
- Well, you could have just said so. - I just did.
不  好好说
No, I mean, ask nicely.
我没有失礼之意啊
I meant no disrespect.
好吧  别再砸东西了
All right. Well, no more smashing.
行吗
Deal?
我保证
You have my word.
很好
Good.
还要那些  伊奇
The usual, please, Lzzy.
你错过了陨石坑那边的精彩时刻
You missed all the excitement out at the crater.
他们说有个卫星掉在沙漠里了
They're saying some kind of satellite landed out in the desert.
我们本来玩得很开心
Yeah, we were having a good time with it
后来政府的人来了
until the Feds showed up.
打扰一下  你们是说有个卫星坠落了吗
Excuse me. Did you say there was a satellite crash?
是的
Yeah.
天啊  这个得传到脸书上  笑一个
Oh, my God. This is going on Facebook. Smile.
那卫星长什么样
What did it look like, the satellite?
不知道是不是卫星  只知道很重
I don't know anything about satellites, but it was heavy.
没人能拿得起它
I mean, nobody could lift it.
他们说它有辐射  我还碰过呢
They said it was radioactive. I had my hands all over it.
怎么走
Which way?
从这往西50英里
Fifty miles west of here.
劝你别去浪费时间
Well, I wouldn't waste my time!
我们走时似乎全军都出动了
Looked like the whole Army was coming when we left.
蠢蛋
Dumbass!
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
-西行50英里处  -为什么
- Fifty miles west of here. - Why?
去拿回属于我的东西
To get what belongs to me.
这么说那卫星成你的了
So you own a satellite now?
它不是他们说的那东西
It's not what they say it is.
不管它是什么
Well, whatever it is,
看来已经被政府控制了
the government seems to think it's theirs. So,
你就打算直冲过去抢回来吗
you just intend to go in there and take it?
是的
Yes.
如果你现在带我去那儿
If you take me there now,
我就告诉你  你想知道的一切
I'll tell you everything you wish to know.
-一切  -没错
- Everything? - Yes.
等我拿回雷神之锤  你就能得到
All the answers you seek will be yours
你寻求的答案
once I reclaim Mjolnir.
咩咩  咩咩是什么
Myeu-muh? What's Myeu-muh?
能跟你说句话吗  简
Can I have a word, Jane?
请别这么做
Please don't do this.
你昨晚不也看到了吗
You saw what I saw last night.
这不是巧合
This is no coincidence.
我们得查明陨石坑里有什么
We have to find out what's in that crater.
我不是在说陨石坑  我在说他
But I'm not talking about the crater, I'm talking about him.
-但他答应告诉我们真相  -他是疯子
- But he's promising us the answers. - He's delusional.
听听他都在说什么
Listen to what he's saying.
他说什么雷神之锤
He's talking about Mjolnir
托尔  彩虹桥
and Thor and Bifrost.
这是我从小听到大的神话
It's the stories I grew up with as a child.
我只是送他去  就这样
I'm just going to drive him. That's it.
他很危险  简
He's dangerous, Jane.
很抱歉  我不能送你去了
I'm sorry, but I can't take you.
那我们就此告别吧
Then this is where we say goodbye.
谢谢
Thank you?
简·福斯特
Jane Foster,
艾瑞克·塞尔维格
Erik Selvig,
达西
Darcy,
再会
farewell.
好吧
All right.
回去干活儿了
Back to work.
那是我的东西
That's my stuff!
这究竟是怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
福斯特小姐  我是神盾局的科尔森特工
Ms. Foster, I'm Agent Coulson with S.H.I.E.L.D.
我应该知道那是什么意思吗
Is that supposed to mean something to me?
-你不能这样做  -简
- You can't do this! - Jane!
简  这比你想的严重多了  别管了
Jane, this is a lot more serious than you realize. Let it go.
别管  这可是我的生活
Let it go? This is my life.
我们在调查一项安全威胁
We're investigating a security threat.
我们得征用
We need to appropriate
你的记录  还有你的大气数据
your records and all your atmospheric data.
"征用"是偷的意思吗
By "appropriate," do you mean steal?
给  这足以弥补你的损失了
Here, this should more than compensate you for your trouble.
这些东西在睿侠可买不到
I can't just buy replacements at Radio Shack,
大部分设备都是我自己组装的
I made most of this equipment myself!
那你肯定能重做一次
Then I'm sure you can do it again.
我肯定也能告你侵犯我的宪法权利
And I'm sure I can sue you for violating my constitutional rights!
抱歉  福斯特小姐  但我们是好人
I'm sorry, Ms. Foster, but we're the good guys.
我们也是
So are we!
我就快弄清一件很了不起的事了
I'm on the verge of understanding something extraordinary.
而关于这现象  我所掌握的一切
And everything I know about this phenomenon
都在这实验室和这本子里了
is either in this lab or in this book.
你不能想拿就拿...
And you can't just take this away...
简  冷静  冷静  简...
Jane! Easy! Easy. Jane...
多谢配合
Thank you for your cooperation.
多年的研究
Years of research,
全没了
gone.
他们还拿走了我的iPod
They even took my iPod.
-备份资料呢  -也被拿了
- What about the backups? - They took our backups.
他们还拿走了备份资料的备份
They took the backups of our backups.
他们做得非常彻底
They were extremely thorough.
我刚下载了三十多首歌
I just downloaded, like, 30 songs onto there.
你能不能别提你的iPod了
Could you please stop with your iPod?
这些到底是什么人啊
Who are these people?
我认识个科学家
I knew this scientist.
是伽玛辐射领域的先驱
The pioneer in gamma radiation.
后来神盾局出现了
S.H.I.E.L.D. showed up
他就杳无音信了
and he wasn't heard from again.
他们不能这样对我们
They're not gonna do that to us.
我要去把东西抢回来
I'm gonna get everything back.
别这样  让我先联系下我的一个同事
Come on, please. Let me contact one of my colleagues.
他之前和这些人接触过
He's had some dealings with these people before.
我给他发邮件  也许他能帮上忙
I'll e-mail him and maybe he can help.
你的笔记本电脑也被拿走了
They took your laptop, too.
众神之父  我们有急事禀报
Allfather, we must speak with you urgently.
我的朋友们
My friends.
奥丁呢
Where's Odin?
父王进入奥丁之眠了
Father has fallen into the Odinsleep.
进入睡眠状态进行恢复和治愈
母后担心他将一觉不醒
Mother fears he may never awaken again.
我们要和她谈话
We would speak with her.
她不肯离开父王床边半步
She has refused to leave my father's bedside.
有急事你们可以直接对我说
You can bring your urgent matter to me.
我现在是你们的王
Your king.
王上  我们恳请您结束对托尔的放逐
My King, we would ask that you end Thor's banishment.
我的首个命令不能与父王的最后命令相悖
My first command cannot be to undo the Allfather's last.
我们就要与约顿海姆开战
We're on the brink of war with Jotunheim.
人民需要看到子承父命
Our people need a sense of continuity,
才能在困难时期拥有安全感
in order to feel safe in these difficult times.
所有人必须齐心合力
All of us must stand together
为阿斯加德而战
for the good of Asgard.
是的  当然
Yes, of course.
很好  那你们等我下令吧
Good. Then you will wait for my word.
容我
If I may
恳请陛下再考虑下...
beg the indulgence of Your Majesty to perhaps reconsider...
够了
We're done!
彩虹桥
周四  托尔日
宠物店
我要匹马
I need a horse!
我们不卖马  只有狗猫鸟...
We don't have horses. Just dogs, cats, birds...
那随便给我头能骑的就好
Then give me one of those large enough to ride.
你还需要搭便车吗
Hey, you still need a lift?
我从未做过这样的事
I've never done anything like this before.
你做过这样的事吗
Have you ever done anything like this before?
经常
Many times.
不过你有这个胆量
But you're brave to do it.
他们偷走了我的毕生心血
Well, they just stole my entire life's work.
我已经别无可失了
I don't really have much left to lose.
但你很聪明
Yeah, but you're clever.
比这个王国的其他人聪明多了
Far more clever than anyone else in this realm.
"王国"  "王国"
"Realm"? "Realm"?
-你觉得我很奇怪  -是的
- You think me strange. - Yeah, I do.
怎么个奇怪法  是好还是坏
Good strange or bad strange?
目前我还不确定
I'm not quite sure yet.
对不起
I'm sorry.
但是  你是谁啊
But who are you?
说真的
Really?
你很快就会知道了
You'll see soon enough.
你答应告诉我答案的
You promised me answers.
你要找的是座桥
What you seek, it's a bridge.
爱因斯坦-罗森桥吗
Like an Einstein-Rosen Bridge?
该说是彩虹桥
More like a Rainbow Bridge.
老天  但愿你没疯
God, I hope you're not crazy.
我真不习惯看到他这样
I never get used to seeing him like this.
他已推迟了太久  我担心...
He's put it off for so long now, that I fear...
这会持续多久
How long will it last?
不知道  这次不一样
I don't know. This time it's different.
我们毫无准备
We were unprepared.
他为什么要骗我
So why did he lie?
他对你保守秘密
He kept the truth from
是不希望你觉得自己是个异类
you so that you would never feel different.
你是我们的儿子  洛基
You are our son, Loki,
我们是你的家人
and we, your family.
我们不能放弃希望
We mustn't lose hope
要相信你父王一定会回到我们身边
that your father will return to us.
还有你哥哥
And your brother.
托尔还有什么希望
What hope is there for Thor?
你父王做任何事都有他的用意
There's always a purpose to everything your father does.
这根本不是卫星坠毁
That's no satellite crash!
否则  他们会拖走残骸
They would have hauled the wreckage away,
而不是在周围搭建设施
they wouldn't have built a city around it.
-你会需要这个的  -什么
- You're going to need this. - What?
等等  为什么
Wait, why?
待在原地
Now stay here.
等我拿回雷神之锤
Once I have Mjolnir,
就把那些被他们抢走的东西还给你
I will return the items they've stolen from you.
好吗
Deal?
不  看看下面的状况
No. Look what's down there.
你觉得你能闯进去把东西夺回来
You think you're just gonna walk in,
再大摇大摆地走出来吗
grab our stuff and walk out?
不  我会飞回来
No. I'm going to fly out.
长官  侦察卫星的信号几乎无法穿透云层
Sir, feed from the keyhole can barely penetrate the cloud cover.
受这东西的干扰
Tech's barely working as it is,
设备本就很难正常运行
with all the interference that thing's giving off.
还有架商业飞机即将飞过上空
And we've got a commercial aircraft coming right over us.
西南航空5434航班
Southwest Airlines, flight 5434.
跟其他航班一样  更改航线
Reroute it like all the others.
稍等
Hold a sec.
西侧围栏外有东西
We've got something outside the fence, west side.
德兰西  我是杰克逊
Delancey, Jackson.
西侧围栏  去检查一下
West side perimeter. Go check it out.
到了
There it is.
德兰西  杰克逊  请回话
Delancey, Jackson. Report.
有人员受伤  围栏遭到破坏
Agent down. We've got a perimeter breach.
我是艾瑞克·塞尔维格博士  有事请留言
You've reached Dr. Erik Selvig. Please leave me a message.
艾瑞克  是我  别担心  我很好
Hi, Erik, it's me. Don't worry, I'm fine, but
但如果一小时内我没联系你
just in case you don't hear from me in the next hour,
就到陨石坑来找我  好吗
just come by the crater site and try and find me, okay?
我正在做你不让我做的事情  对不起
I did exactly what you told me not to. I'm sorry.
非常抱歉  再见
So sorry. Bye.
B区  行动
Bravo quadrant, move!
已进入南侧通道
Entering south tunnel!
不行  通讯中断
Negative, negative. I have no comms.
发现目标  东侧通道
Target sighted, east tunnel!
派一个人到高处  带上枪
I need eyes up high, with a gun.
朝北去了
Moving north!
怎么了
What have we got?
那玩意发出了
There's a massive electromagnetic surge
强电磁涌
coming off that thing.
系统几乎无法承受
Systems are barely coping.
巴顿  请回话
Barton? Talk to me.
要我击倒他吗  长官
You want me to slow him down, sir?
还是要派更多人去被他打趴
Or are you sending in more guys for him to beat up?
稍后给你指令
I'll let you know.
你块头还真大
You're big.
但我打过更大的
Fought bigger.
快下令  科尔森
Better call it, Coulson,
我开始喜欢这家伙了
'cause I'm starting to root for this guy.
最后的机会  长官
Last chance, sir.
等等  我想看看
Wait. I want to see this.
好了  表演结束  地面部队出动
All right, show's over. Ground units, move in.
他犯了罪  他进了监狱
He committed a crime. He's in jail!
-我不能把他丢在那儿  -为什么
- I can't just leave him there! - Why?
你没看到我看到的一切
You didn't see what I saw!
快看  快看  雷神之锤
Look! Look, it's Mjolnir.
你在哪找到的
Where'd you find this?
童书区
The children's section.
我想让你明白他的故事有多蠢
I just wanted to show you how silly his story was.
可你一直谆谆教导我
But you're the one who's always pushing me
要探索每一个可能  每一种解释
to chase down every possibility, every alternative!
我是让你探索科学  不是魔法
I'm talking about science, not magic!
魔法是我们还无法解释的科学
Well, magic's just science that we don't understand yet.
亚瑟·C·克拉克的名言
Arthur C. Clarke.
他是科幻小说作家
Who wrote science fiction.
-是科学真理的先驱  -个别时候而已
- A precursor to science fact! - In some cases, yeah.
如果确实存在爱因斯坦-罗森桥
Well, if there is an Einstein-Rosen Bridge,
那另一端一定有别的世界
then there's something on the other side.
更先进的生物可以穿过它
And advanced beings could have crossed it!
简
Jane.
原始的维京人
A primitive culture like the Vikings
可能将他们敬为了神灵
might have worshipped them as deities.
对  对  没错  谢谢你
Yes! Yes, exactly. Thank you.
你把我的人
You made my men,
一些全世界最训练有素的职业人员
some of the most highly trained professionals in the world,
比得像拿最低工资的超市保安
look like a bunch of minimum-wage mall cops.
这很伤人
That's hurtful.
根据我的经验
In my experience,
得是受过类似训练的人
it takes someone who's received similar training
才能像你那样打倒他们
to do what you did to them.
告诉我你是在哪里受的训练
Why don't you tell me where you received your training?
巴基斯坦  车臣  还是阿富汗
Pakistan? Chechnya? Afghanistan?
你看上去更像是雇佣兵
No, you strike me more as the soldier of fortune type.
哪里的  南非吗
Where was it? South Africa?
有些组织会花大价钱
Certain groups pay very well
雇佣你这么优秀的佣兵
for a good mercenary like you.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
无论如何
One way or another,
我们都会得到我们想要的信息
we find out what we need to know.
这我们很在行
We're good at that.
别乱跑
Don't go anywhere.
洛基  你怎么会来这里
Loki! What are you doing here?
我得来见见你
I had to see you.
发生了什么事
What's happened?
告诉我  是约顿海姆的事吗
Tell me. Is it Jotunheim?
让我去和父王解释
Let me explain to Father.
父王已经死了
Father is dead.
什么
What?
对你的驱逐
Your banishment,
战争再起的威胁
the threat of a new war,
让他难以承受
it was too much for him to bear.
你不要自责
You mustn't blame yourself.
我知道你爱他
I know that you loved him.
我也劝过他  但他听不进去
I tried to tell him so, but he wouldn't listen.
明知你已无法拿起雷神之锤
It was so cruel to put the hammer within your reach,
还放在你眼前  实在残忍
knowing that you could never lift it.
现在王位的重担落在了我肩上
The burden of the throne has fallen to me now.
我能回家吗
Can I come home?
和约顿海姆的休战条件就是永远放逐你
The truce with Jotunheim is conditional upon your exile.
好吧  但难道没有别的办法...
Yes, but couldn't we find a way...
母后也不允许你回家
And Mother has forbidden your return.
我是来告别的  哥哥
This is goodbye, Brother.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
不
No.
该道歉的是我
I am sorry.
谢谢你来见我
Thank you for coming here.
永别了
Farewell.
再见
Goodbye.
Goodbye?
我才刚回来
I just got back.
长官
Sir?
有人要见他
He's got a visitor.
他的名字是唐纳德·布莱克吗
His name is Donald Blake?
唐纳德·布莱克博士
Dr. Donald Blake.
你的同事还真危险  塞尔维格博士
You have dangerous coworkers, Dr. Selvig.
他得知你们拿走了
He was distraught when he found out
我们所有的研究资料后心急如焚
that you've taken all our research.
那是他一生的心血  就这样没了
That was years of his life, gone!
你该明白  人遇到那种事都会爆发
You can understand how a man could go off like that.
像你们这种庞大的秘密组织
A big, faceless organization like yours
带着一群穿长靴的暴徒闯进来...
coming in with their jackbooted thugs and...
他是这么说的
That's how he put it.
这也不足以解释
That still doesn't explain
他是如何突破我们的安保系统的
how he managed to tear through our security.
兴奋剂呗  他特别喜欢健身
Steroids! He's a bit of a fitness nut.
长官
Sir?
伪造信息
系统显示他是个医学博士
It says here that he's an M.D.
他是  他以前是
Well, he is! Or he was.
他后来转行当了一名物理学家
He switched careers and became a physicist.
杰出的物理学家
A brilliant physicist.
他是个很棒的人  经历了很多磨难
He's a wonderful man. He's a man in pain.
唐尼  唐尼  唐尼
Donny, Donny, Donny!
你在这儿啊  你会没事的
There you are. You're gonna be all right.
我这就带你回家
I'm taking you home now.
塞尔维格博士
Dr. Selvig!
让他别再靠近围栏了
Just keep him away from the bars.
我会的
I will!
-我们去哪  -去喝一杯
- Where are we going? - To get a drink.
跟着他们
Follow them.
我全搞错了
You know, I had it all backwards.
全错了
I had it all wrong.
发现自己不知道
It's not a bad thing finding
所有的答案  并不是件坏事
out that you don't have all the answers.
你会开始问正确的问题
You start asking the right questions.
这是我人生中第一次
For the first time in my life,
不知道接下来该干什么
I have no idea what I'm supposed to do.
任何人想在这世上找到属于自己的道路
Anyone who's ever going to find his way in this world
都得先承认他不知自己究竟身在何处
has to start by admitting he doesn't know where the hell he is.
谢谢你的帮助
Thank you for what you've done.
不  不用谢我  我这么做是为了简
No, don't thank me. I only did it for Jane.
她爸爸和我曾在一所大学教书
Her father and I taught at university together.
他是个好男人
He was a good man.
听不进别人的话
He never listened.
我也是
Neither did I.
我父亲本想教育我
My father was trying to teach me something,
但我太迟钝了
but I was too stupid to see it.
我不知道你是有妄想症
I don't know if you're delusional
还是在耍什么花招
or if you're pulling some kind of con,
我不在乎
I don't care.
我只在乎她
I just care about her.
我看到她看你的眼神了
I've seen the way she looks at you.
我对你发誓  我无意伤害她
I swear to you, I mean her no harm.
很好
Good.
这样的话  我再请你喝一杯
In that case, I'll buy you another round,
然后你今晚就离开小镇
and you leave town tonight.
两杯酒鬼炸弹
Two boilermakers.
杀了他
Kill him.
都不顾我为你做了那么多吗
After all I've done for you?
原来是你指引我们进入阿斯加德的
So you're the one who showed us the way into Asgard.
说实话  那只是找点乐子
That was just a bit of fun, really.
为了毁掉我哥哥的大日子
To ruin my brother's big day.
保护我们的王国
And to protect the realm
能再晚些承受他愚蠢的统治
from his idiotic rule for a while longer.
我洗耳恭听
I will hear you.
我会掩护你和你几个手下
I will conceal you and a handful of your soldiers,
带你们进入奥丁的房间
lead you into Odin's chambers,
你就可以杀了卧床的他
and you can slay him where he lies.
你为什么不自己杀了他
Why not kill him yourself?
我想阿斯加德人不会愿意接受
I suspect that the Asgardians would not take kindly
一个谋害先王的国王吧
to a king who had murdered his predecessor.
等奥丁死了
Once Odin is dead,
我就把远古冬棺还给你
I will return the Casket to you
你就可以让约顿海姆恢复...
and you can return Jotunheim to all its...
昔日光辉
glory.
我
I...
接受
accept.
你怎么了  门卫
What troubles you, Gatekeeper?
你在约顿海姆时  我试图看你
I turned my gaze upon you in Jotunheim,
但却看不见也听不见
but could neither see you nor hear you.
你被遮蔽了
You were shrouded from me,
就像侵入这里的冰霜巨人那样
like the Frost Giants that entered this realm.
也许你是任职太久
Perhaps your senses have weakened
感官退化了吧
after your many years of service.
也可能是有人找到了办法
Or perhaps someone has found a way
隐藏不想被我看到的东西
to hide that which he does not wish me to see.
你有强大的力量  海姆达尔
You have great power, Heimdall.
奥丁曾畏惧过你吗
Did Odin ever fear you?
-没有  -为什么
- No. - And why is that?
因为他是我的国王  我誓死服从他
Because he is my king and I am sworn to obey him.
他曾经是你的国王  现在你要服从我了
He was your king and you're sworn to obey me now.
对吗
Yes?
是的
Yes.
那就不准为任何人开启彩虹桥
Then you will open the Bifrost to no one
直到我收拾好我哥留下的烂摊子
until I have repaired the damage that my brother has done.
天哪  他还好吗
Oh, my God. Is he okay?
他很好  毫发无伤
He's fine. Not injured at all.
真抱歉  我的朋友
I'm sorry, my friend.
-怎么回事  -我们喝酒了  打了一架
- What happened? - We drank, we fought,
他给家族争光了
he made his ancestors proud.
把他放到床上去
Put him on the bed.
我还是不相信你是雷神
I still don't think you're the God of Thunder.
但你应该是
But you ought to be.
这是你的住所吗
Are these your chambers?
说是临时住所更合适
It's more of a temporary living situation.
抱歉  一般没客人会来
I'm sorry. I don't usually have guests.
事实上  从没来过客人
Actually, I never have guests.
放错地方了
That's not the right place for it.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们出去吧
Can we go outside?
好啊  当然
Yes, of course.
我睡不着时就会来这里
I come up here sometimes when I can't sleep
或是整理粒子数据的时候
or I'm trying to reconcile particle data,
又或是达西快把我逼疯的时候
or when Darcy's driving me crazy.
仔细想想  我其实经常来这里
I come up here a lot, actually, now that I think about it.
真高兴你没事
I'm really glad you're safe.
你对我很好
You've been very kind to me,
而相比之下  我的表现太不知感恩了
and I've been far less grateful than you deserve.
我开车撞了你几次
Well, I hit you with my car a couple times,
我们算是扯平了
so I think that kind of evens things out.
也许是我活该被撞
Perhaps I had it coming.
天哪
Oh, my God!
难以置信
I don't believe it!
我只能拿回这些
It was all I could get back.
很抱歉没能兑现我的承诺
I'm sorry it's not as much as I promised.
不  这很棒了  这...
No, no, this is great! This is...
我不用再从头开始了
I don't have to start from scratch now.
谢谢你
Thank you.
怎么了
What's wrong?
神盾局  不管他们是什么组织
S.H.I.E.L.D. Whatever they are,
都会尽一切办法
they're gonna do everything in their power
使我们的研究无法得见天日
to make sure this research never sees the light of day.
不  简
No, Jane.
听我说  你不能放弃
Listen to me. You must not give up.
-要有始有终  -为什么
- You must finish what you've started. - Why?
因为你是正确的
Because you're right.
来  你看
Here, look.
你们的祖先称之为魔法
Your ancestors called it magic,
你称之为科学
and you call it science.
在我的家乡
Well, I come from a place
它们两者是同样的东西
where they're one and the same thing.
这是什么
What is that?
我父王是这样对我解释的
My father explained it to me like this,
你们的世界
that your world
是宇宙九大王国之一
is one of the Nine Realms of the Cosmos,
连接各王国的是世界树的枝干
linked to each other by the branches of Yggdrasil,
也就是世界之树
the Worlds Tree.
你们每天都看到它  但不自知
Now you see it every day without realizing.
这些拍到图像  用...
The images glimpsed through...
你们叫它什么来着
What did you call it?
"呼伯望远镜"
This Hooble Telescope.
-哈勃  -哈勃望远镜
- Hubble. - Hubble Telescope.
再说点吧
Tell me more.
九大王国
So, the Nine Realms.
这里是米德加德  也就是地球
Now, there is Midgard, which is Earth.
这里是艾尔夫海姆
This is Alfheim.
这是华纳海姆
Vanaheim.
这是约顿海姆
Jotunheim.
这是阿斯加德
And Asgard.
这就是我的家
And that's where I come from.
谢谢你  简
Thank you, Jane.
我们的挚友被驱逐了  洛基登上了王位
Our dearest friend banished, Loki on the throne,
阿斯加德面临战祸  而你却在这儿大吃大喝
Asgard on the brink of war, yet you've managed to consume
四只野猪  六只雉鸡  半只牛
four wild boar, six pheasant, a side of beef,
还有两大桶麦酒  我都替你脸红
and two casks of ale. Shame on you.
你就什么都不在乎吗
Don't you care?
别把我的胃口理解成冷漠
Do not mistake my appetite for apathy!
你们两个  够了
Stop it, both of you!
别闹了
Stop.
-我们都清楚该做什么  -我们得行动
- We all know what we have to do. - We must go.
我们得找到托尔
We must find Thor.
那是叛国罪
It's treason.
去他的叛国  那是自杀
To hell with treason, it's suicide.
托尔也会为我们铤而走险的
Thor would do the same for us.
别说了
Now shush.
海姆达尔可能在监视我们呢
Heimdall might be watching.
海姆达尔要见你们
Heimdall demands your presence.
我们死定了
We're doomed.
你们想违抗我们的国王洛基的命令
You would defy the commands of Loki, our king,
打破作为战士曾许下的誓言
break every oath you have taken as warriors,
犯下叛国罪把托尔带回来吗
and commit treason to bring Thor back?
-是的  -很好
- Yes. - Good.
你要帮我们吗
So you'll help us?
我必须效忠国王
I am bound by honor to our king.
我不能为你们开启彩虹桥
I cannot open the bridge to you.
这家伙真难懂  是吧
Complicated fellow, isn't he?
现在我们怎么办
Now what do we do?
你们看
Look!
-刚刚那是什么鬼  -我不知道  长官
- What the hell was that? - I don't know, sir.
刚才突然探测到了超强的能量
We got massive energy readings out of nowhere
然后又突然消失
and then they just disappeared.
大概在西北方15英里处
Fifteen miles due northwest.
我们去看看
Let's go take a look.
谢谢
Thank you.
-谢谢  -乐意效劳
- Thank you. - You're very welcome.
总部呼叫2队  我们在城外发现异常
Base to Team 2, we've got activity outside the town.
盯住你们的目标
Stay on your target.
确保我哥哥回不来
Ensure my brother does not return.
摧毁一切
Destroy everything.
妈妈
Mom?
镇上有文艺复兴节吗
Is there a Renaissance Fair in town?
报告总部
Call it in.
总部  我们发现了战士公主西娜
Base, we've got Xena,
成龙和罗宾汉
Jackie Chan and Robin Hood.
这是很棒的理论  简
It's a beautiful theory, Jane.
但你别想
But you won't be able to
说服科学界相信
convince the scientific community of any of it.
除非你有证据
Not without hard evidence.
找到你了
Found you!
我的朋友们
My friends!
太好了  太好了
This is good! This is good.
难以置信
I don't believe it.
容我介绍一下  希芙女士和三位勇士
Excuse me. Lady Sif and the Warriors Three.
我的朋友们
My friends,
我真高兴能见到你们
I've never been happier to see anyone.
但你们不该来
But you should not have come.
我们来带你回家
We're here to take you home.
你们知道我不能回去
You know I can't go home.
我的父王
My father is
因我而死
dead because of me.
我必须继续被流放
And I must remain in exile.
托尔
Thor,
你父王还活着
your father still lives.
告诉我  洛基
Tell me, Loki,
你怎么把约顿巨人带进阿斯加德的
how did you get the Jotuns into Asgard?
你以为彩虹桥是进出王国的
You think the Bifrost is the only way
唯一途径吗
in and out of this realm?
各个王国间有很多密道
There are secret paths between the worlds
哪怕你天赋异禀也看不到
to which even you, with all your gifts, are blind.
但我已经不再需要它们了  我是国王了
But I have need of them no longer, now that I am king.
我宣布  因为你的叛国行为
And I say, for your act of treason,
免除你门卫的职务
you are relieved of your duties as Gatekeeper,
你不再是阿斯加德的公民了
and no longer citizen of Asgard.
那我就不用听命于你了
Then I need no longer obey you.
找语言学部的人来看看
Get somebody from Linguistics down here.
还有其他人要来吗
Was somebody else coming?
是斯塔克的吗
Is that one of Stark's?
不知道  他什么都不跟我说
I don't know. The guy never tells me anything.
你好
Hello.
你正在使用未登记的武器科技
You are using unregistered weapons technology.
请表明身份
Identify yourself.
没事啦
Here we go.
快跑
Incoming!
简  你们快走
Jane, you have to leave.
-你呢  -我要留在这儿
- What are you gonna do? - I'm staying here.
托尔要和我们并肩作战
Thor's going to fight with us!
我的朋友们
My friends,
我现在肉体凡胎  我只会碍手碍脚
I'm just a man. I'll only be in the way,
甚至连累你们
or worse, get one of you killed.
但我能帮他们转移去安全的地方
But I can help get these people to safety.
如果你要留下  我也留下
Well, if you're staying, then so am I.
-我们需要点时间  -我们帮你争取时间
- We'll need some time. - You'll have it!
好吧  大家快走吧
Okay, move it, people!
大家都出去  从后门走
Everybody out! Use the back door.
快走  回头再吃
Go, hurry! You can eat later.
分散他的注意力
Keep it distracted.
为了阿斯加德
For Asgard!
撤退
Fall back!
跑  快跑
Go. Now. Run!
希芙  希芙  你已经尽力了
Sif. Sif, you've done all you can.
不  死也要死得像个战士
No. I will die a warrior's death.
历史会记住这一刻的
Stories will be told of this day.
活下去  自己讲述这段历史
Live, and tell those stories yourself.
快跑
Now go.
你们得回阿斯加德  去阻止洛基
You must return to Asgard. You have to stop Loki.
那你怎么办
What about you?
别担心  朋友们  我自有打算
Do not worry, my friends. I have a plan.
走吧
Come on.
我们快撤退  快走
We need to fall back. Come on.
走啊
Come on.
等等
Wait!
他要干什么
What's he doing?
弟弟  不管我怎样委屈了你
Brother, whatever I have done to wrong you,
不管我做了什么让你这样
whatever I have done to lead you to do this,
我真的很抱歉
I am truly sorry.
但这些人是无辜的
But these people are innocent.
杀了他们对你没有任何好处
Taking their lives will gain you nothing.
杀了我吧
So take mine
然后到此为止
and end this.
不
No.
结束了
It's over.
不  没结束
No. It's not over.
我是说  你安全了
I mean, you're safe.
我们都很安全
We're safe.
那就行了
It's over.
不
No.
-出现峰值  -读数上升
- We're spiking. - Levels increase!
不管是谁持有此锤
Whosoever holds this hammer,
只要他配得上
if he be worthy,
就将拥有雷神之力
shall possess the power of Thor.
简
Jane!
不
No.
-过来  -不
- Come! - No.
-快走  -不
天啊
Oh. My. God.
这才是你平时的装束吗
So, is this how you normally look?
差不多吧
More or less.
挺帅的
It's a good look.
我们得去彩虹桥的落点
We must go to the Bifrost site.
我有话和我弟弟说
I would have words with my brother.
打扰一下
Excuse me!
唐纳德
Donald?
我认为你没对我说实话
I don't think you've been completely honest with me.
听着  科尔之子
Know this, Son of Coul.
之前讲的起名习惯
托尔以为科尔森的名字也是这个意思
你和我  我们都是在为
You and I, we fight for the same cause,
保护这个世界而战
the protection of this world.
从今天起  我与你结盟
From this day forward, you can count me as your ally
但你得把你拿走的简的东西还回来
if you return the items you have taken from Jane.
-偷走的  -借用而已
- Stolen. - Borrowed.
好吧  你可以拿回你的设备
Of course, you can have your equipment back.
这样你才能继续你的研究
You're gonna need it to continue your research.
你想看我跟你说过的那座桥吗
Would you like to see the bridge we spoke of?
当然
Sure.
等等  我还有事要问你
Wait, I need to debrief you!
欢迎来到阿斯加德
Welcome to Asgard.
海姆达尔  开启彩虹桥
Heimdall, open the Bifrost.
海姆达尔
Heimdall?
Heimdall!
他不回应
He doesn't answer.
那我们就被困在这了
Then we are stranded.
海姆达尔  你能听见吗  我们需要你
Heimdall! If you can hear me, we need you now!
海姆达尔  我们需要你
Heimdall! We need you now!
海姆达尔
Heimdall!
我必须回阿斯加德去  但我向你保证
I must go back to Asgard, but I give you my word,
我会回来找你的
I will return for you.
好吗
Deal?
好的
Deal.
带他去疗伤
Get him to the healing room!
我去找我弟弟
Leave my brother to me.
据说
It's said
你依然能看见  听见周遭发生的事情
you can still hear and see what transpires around you.
希望这是真的
I hope it's true,
那样你就会知道
so that you may know
你是死在
your death came at the hand
劳菲手里
of Laufey.
而你是死在奥丁之子手里
And your death came by the son of Odin.
洛基
Loki!
你救了你父王
You saved him!
我向你发誓  母后
I swear to you, Mother,
他们会为今天的所作所为付出代价
that they will pay for what they've done today.
洛基
Loki.
托尔
Thor!
我就知道你会回来的
I knew you'd return to us.
你为什么不告诉她
Why don't you tell her
你是怎么派毁灭者去杀我和我们的朋友
how you sent the Destroyer to kill our friends, to kill me?
什么
What?
它一定是执行了父王最后的命令
Why, it must have been enforcing Father's last command.
你是个厉害的骗子  一直都是
You're a talented liar, Brother. Always have been.
你回来了真好
It's good to have you back.
失陪了  我得去摧毁约顿海姆
Now if you'll excuse me, I have to destroy Jotunheim.
你阻止不了的
You can't stop it.
彩虹桥会一直开启到约顿海姆被撕碎
The Bifrost will build until it rips Jotunheim apart.
简
Jane?
你为什么这么做
Why have you done this?
证明给父王看  我才是他的好儿子
To prove to Father that I am the worthy son.
等他醒来时  是我救了他命
When he wakes, I will have saved his life.
还杀死了那一族的怪物
I will have destroyed that race of monsters.
我会成为王位的真正继承人
And I will be true heir to the throne!
你不能消灭一整个种族
You can't kill an entire race!
为什么不能
Why not?
你怎么对冰霜巨人突然产生好感了
And what is this newfound love for the Frost Giants?
你以前可是会赤手空拳把他们杀光
You could have killed them all with your bare hands.
-我变了  -我也是
- I've changed. - So have I.
来打我啊
Now fight me.
我从来没想要王位
I never wanted the throne!
我只想得到和你一样的对待
I only ever wanted to be your equal.
我不会和你打的  弟弟
I will not fight you, Brother!
我不是你弟弟
I'm not your brother.
从来都不是
I never was.
洛基  这简直疯了
Loki, this is madness.
是吗
Is it madness?
疯狂吗
Is it?
拜托  你在地球上遭遇了什么
Come on. What happened to you on Earth
把你变得这么懦弱
that turned you so soft?
别跟我说是因为那个女人
Don't tell me it was that woman.
还真是
It was!
也许  等我们结束了这一切
Well, maybe, when we're finished here,
我会亲自去看看她
I'll pay her a visit myself!
托尔
Thor!
哥哥  救我
Brother, please.
够了
Enough!
看看你
Look at you,
强大的托尔
the Mighty Thor,
力大无穷
with all your strength,
现在对你又有何用
and what good does it do you now?
你听到了吗  哥哥  你什么都做不了
Do you hear me, Brother? There's nothing you can do!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
如果你毁了彩虹桥  你就再也见不到她了
If you destroy the bridge, you'll never see her again!
原谅我  简
Forgive me, Jane.
我本可以做到的  父王
I could have done it, Father!
我本可以做到的
I could have done it!
为了你
For you!
为了大家
For all of us!
不  洛基
No, Loki.
洛基  不要
Loki, no.
不
No!
No.
结束了
It's gone.
然后  我一声大吼
And then, with a mighty bellow,
飞进了铁巨人的体内  把他放倒了
I flew into the giant metal creature and laid him low!
那是摔了个四脚朝天的意思吗
Is that another way of saying you fell on your huge ass?
事实上
As a matter of fact,
摔倒只是蒙蔽毁灭者的策略
falling was a tactic lulling the Destroyer...
王后陛下  您儿子的事我很遗憾
My Queen, I'm so sorry for your loss.
他怎么样了
How is he?
他在悼念他的弟弟
He mourns for his brother.
还有...
And...
他思念她
He misses her.
那个凡人
The mortal.
你将会是个明君
You'll be a wise king.
不会再有比你更贤明的君主
There will never be a wiser king than you.
和更完美的父亲了
Or a better father.
我有很多要学的
I have much to learn.
我现在知道了
I know that now.
也许有一天
Someday, perhaps,
我会让你以我为傲
I shall make you proud.
你已经让我骄傲了
You've already made me proud.
我们再也到不了地球了
So Earth is lost to us.
不
No.
希望总是有的
There is always hope.
你能看到她吗
Can you see her?
能
Yes.
我拿了粒子探测仪
I have the particle detectors!
达西  你拿神盾局的卫星密码了吗
Darcy, do you have the S.H.I.E.L.D. satellite codes?
嗯  你看见我的电击枪了吗
Yeah. Have you seen my Taser?
她还好吗
How is she?
上车  走吧  简
In the car. Come on, Jane!
她在找你
She searches for you.
雷    神
塞尔维格博士
Dr. Selvig.
你就是那个幕后主脑吗
So you're the man behind all this?
这里像个迷宫
It's quite a labyrinth.
我还以为他们要带我来杀了我
I was thinking they're taking me down here to kill me.
我听说了新墨西哥州的事
I've been hearing about the New Mexico situation.
你的工作让很多比我聪明的人
Your work has impressed a lot of people
非常倾佩
who are much smarter than I am.
我手里的资料多
I have a lot to work with.
福斯特的理论  通往另一个世界的通道
The Foster Theory. A gateway to another dimension.
这是前所未有的
It's unprecedented.
不是吗
Isn't it?
传说和历史之间总是有区别
Legend tells us one thing, history, another.
但也有时候
But every now and then,
两者会发生重叠
we find something that belongs to both.
这是什么
What is it?
力量  博士
Power, Doctor.
如果我们能弄清怎么利用它
If we can figure out how to tap it,
也许就能拥有无尽的力量
maybe unlimited power.
我想这值得一试
Well, I guess that's worth a look.